# **Nestor Sanchez**

# I am a Diagnostic Medical Sonographer with over 10 years of experience in the medical imaging field

Santee, CA elmasvergon619@icloud.com - (909)697-8924

To obtain the challenging position of Diagnostic Medical Sonographer, where I may utilize and expand upon experience gained from past employment.

I am a highly talented self-motivated, bi-lingual individual who possesses work experience in the field of diagnostic medical sonography, vascular sonography, and interventional procedures with a strong ability to integrate laboratory results, patient history and medical records for optimal patient outcome.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Sonographer

Doctors Hospital of Laredo - Laredo, TX - November 2012 to May 2013

Performed clinical assessment and diagnostic sonography examination. Used cognitive sonographic skills to identify, record, and adapt procedures as appropriate to anatomical, pathological, diagnostic information and images. Use independent judgement during the sonographic examination to accurately differentiate between normal and pathologic findings. Monitor patient comfort level during testing and follow and establish policies and procedures to ensure the care and safety of the patient while undergoing ultrasound examination. Assisted Radiologist in performing special procedures such as Abcess drainage, biopsies, and ultrasound guided central line placement.

#### Sonographer

Medica Imaging INC - Pico Rivera, CA - February 2012 to November 2012

with Interventional Examinations

Performed ABD, OBGYN, Small Parts, and Vascular Ultrasounds

Maintained Appropriate Stock of all Ultrasound Inventory

Generated Daily Log of all Examinations Performed within Department

## Sonographer

San Ysidro Health Center - San Ysidro, CA - May 2010 to August 2011

Performed Carotid Intimal-Medial Thickness Examinations

Received and prepared participant for examination by reviewing history, and explaining method of testing, and adjusting participant for anatomically correct positioning

Completed research questionnaire forms with participants for data collection

Performed ankle brachial index as part of protocol

Maintained daily log of all examinations performed and participants completed

#### Sonographer

Scripps Mercy Medical Center - Chula Vista, CA - June 2004 to May 2010

Chula Vista, CA Radiology/Diagnostic Imaging

Diagnostic Medical Sonographer June 2004-May 2010

Perform clinical assessment and diagnostic sonography examinations.

Use cognitive sonographic skills to identify, record, and adapt procedures as appropriate to anatomical, pathological, diagnostic information and images.

Use independent judgment during the sonographic examination to accurately differentiate between normal and pathologic findings.

Analyze sonograms, synthesize sonographic information and medical history, and communicate findings to the appropriate physician.

Coordinate work schedule with Department Director and scheduling desk to assure workload coverage.

Assume responsibility for the safety, mental and physical comfort of patients while they are in the sonographers care.

Assist with the daily operations of the sonographic laboratory.

Maintain a daily log of patients seen / complete exam billing forms.

Maintain ultrasound equipment and work area, and maintain adequate supplies.

Establish and maintain ethical working relationships and good rapport with all interrelating hospitals, referral or commercial agencies.

Assist interventional Radiologist with invasive procedures; Liver biopsies,

Renal biopsies, Renal Transplant, Thyroid biopsies, Venous ablation, Ultrasound Guided Thoracentesis and Ultrasound Guided Paracentesis.

Assume responsibility for supervision and training of ultrasound students.

Assume responsibility for supervision and training of new staff members.

Assume role of English/Spanish translations pertaining to all invasive and non-invasive procedures performed in diagnostic lab.

#### Sonographer

Mercy Medical Center - Merced, CA - June 2003 to June 2004

Merced, CA Radiology/Diagnostic Imaging

Diagnostic Medical Sonographer June 2003-June 2004

Received and prepared patient for examinations by reviewing requisition and case history, assessing method of testing, and explaining procedure to patient.

Perform ultrasound scans including abdomen, pelvis, thyroid, and other examinations as required.

Prepared the preliminary sonographer reports and assessed the technical quality and completeness of ultrasounds performed.

Monitored patient comfort level during testing and followed established policies and procedures to ensure the care and safety of the patient while undergoing ultrasound examinations.

Operated ultrasonographic and related equipment according to established procedures, maintained equipment in proper working order and reported all equipment failures to the Ultrasound Supervisor or Site Manager.

Assisted the Radiologist in performing special procedures such as abscess drainages, biopsies, and ultrasound guided central line placement.

#### Sonographer

Amarillo, TX - Northwest, Texas, US - May 2002 to June 2003

Radiology/Diagnostic Imaging

Diagnostic Medical Sonographer May 2002-June 2003

Established and maintained ethical working relationships and good rapport with all interrelating hospitals and medical facilities.

Assisted the radiologist and other health care professionals in related technical areas as needed.

Performed diagnostic testing including: OB/GYN, Pelvic, Abdomen, Small Parts, Venous lower, Venous upper, Arterial lower, Arterial upper, Saphenous Vein mapping, Cephalic Vein mapping, Carotid ultrasounds.

Completed high quality tests; generated reports; kept record and performed all related support activities.

# **EDUCATION**

# **Medical Technician Certification**

School Of Continuing Education - Corona, CA August 1993 to August 1996

# **Diploma**

Victor Valley College - Apple Valley, CA September 1989 to June 1993